# HAMMAD HASSAN

Birmingham, United Kingdom 07554830329 - hammad.hsn7991@gmail.com

**Permit:** International | **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/hammad-hassan-51567b299/

Portfolio: <a href="https://hammad7991-portfolio.netlify.app/">https://hammad7991-portfolio.netlify.app/</a> | https://github.com/HammadHassan7991

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

As a Full Stack Developer with 2 years of experience, I possess significant proficiency in front-end and back-end development using React, Next.js, Node.js, and Javascript. Driven by an unwavering passion for web development, I am committed to working in a stimulating and challenging environment that fosters continuous learning and skills enhancement. I am enthusiastic about contributing my expertise towards achieving the company's growth objectives and making a meaningful impact in the industry.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

08/2022 - 09/2023

# Full Stack Developer, Tripsheperd, Niagara Falls Canada

- Led the development of company's internal admin system using React and GraphQL as backend, improving the efficiency of managing reservations.
- Built a solution with Rezdy to synchronize product availability across OTAs like Viator, Expedia, GetYourGuide and Airbnb, saving operational cost.
- Developed a fully optimized tour booking website for the company using Next.js and also integrated payment gateways into the products.
- Implemented user authentication using JWT and Next Auth0, with multiple user roles, and authorization.
- Proficiently integrated Google Maps API to create location-based features within applications, enabling location sharing feature across apps on multiple platforms.
- Integrated the headless CMS Strapi with database using remote schemas for real-time updates and personalized content delivery.
- Developed push notifications pipelines for cross-platform products.
- Implemented cross-site protection using CSFR token and SSL encryption.
- Integrated Google Analytics through GCP for payment tracking and SEO optimization purpose.
- Wrote unit test codes using Mocha, and contributed to the development and maintenance of databases, ensuring that they were secure, scalable, and efficient.

#### 01/2021 - 02/2022

### Front-End Developer, Secure Residence Pvt Ltd, Islamabad

- Developed and launched a real estate platform using React and Firebase, resulting in notable increase in user engagement and retention.
- Built an internal property-sharing system for realtors, enhancing collaboration and increasing sales by optimizing inventory management.
- Designed and implemented advanced user authentication and security features, improving data protection and building user trust.
- Developed in-app chat communication using WebSockets, enabling real-time customer service interactions.
- Integrated local payment systems to enable smooth and hassle-free financial transactions.
- Created a global search feature that enables quick access to relevant information across the entire system, significantly enhancing user experience.

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Javascript, Python, Typescript, HTML, Tailwind, CSS, Sass.
- React, Next.js, Node.js, Redux, Redux-Toolkit, Redux-Saga.
- SQL, GraphQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, AWS, Hasura.
- Dockers, Git/Github, Mocha, Jira, Taskade.

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES**

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner.
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, MongoDB) By Maximilian Schwarzmüller, Udemy.
- Master the (Data Structures + Algorithms) by Andrei Neagoie, Udemy.
- Complete React Developer in 2023 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) by Andrei Neagoie, Udemy

# **EDUCATION**

09/2023 - Current

Master of Science: Data Analytics
Aston University - Birmingham, BIR

09/2015 - 08/2019

Bachelor of Science: Telecommunication
Hitec University Taxila - Pakistan

# LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu/Hindi

# Reference

Arif Ali – Scrum Master ,Tripsheperd arif@tripsheperd.com